<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Bram van Ginneken</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Bram van Ginneken</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thira Lab</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/thira-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/thira-lab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;icai&#34;&gt;ICAI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icai.ai/&#34;&gt;ICAI&lt;/a&gt; labs are a concept initiated at the University of Amsterdam to encourage more collaborations between Dutch universities and companies and societal organizations in the area of artificial intelligence. It&amp;rsquo;s something I always tried to do in my own research group, because the only way to bring the results of our research to the clinic is by working with companies. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen many attempts by academics to do that themselves, providing their software to doctors, maintaining support for that software, and this tends to fail, unfortunately. Companies have been co-funding my research from the beginning, but the ICAI concept gave me an opportunity to take this to the next level. An ICAI lab has at least 5 PhD students and it&amp;rsquo;s a great vehicle to showcase your collaboration with companies in your field. When I learned about it, I started talking to the ICAI people and we decided to set up the first such lab in Nijmegen: Thira Lab. It was a collaboration between my group, &lt;a href=&#34;https://delft.care/&#34;&gt;Delft Imaging&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://thirona.eu/&#34;&gt;Thirona&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biography #1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;youth&#34;&gt;Youth&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I grew up in the south of the Netherlands, in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nuenen&#34;&gt;Nuenen&lt;/a&gt;, a village best known for the fact that Vincent van Gogh was unhappy there for a few years of his life. The second most famous person from Nuenen, dixit Wikipedia, is a computer scientist! Edsger W. Dijkstra lived a few streets away from where I was born. My niece was his neighbor for a while. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.utexas.edu/users/EWD/&#34;&gt;E. W. Dijkstra Archive&lt;/a&gt; is amazing. It has a lot of handwritten manuscripts, even from after 2000. Because, after all, a real computer scientist only needs a pencil and a piece of paper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
